skipton.co.uk 2012-05-13

# Important Security Cookie & Privacy Policy- Skipton My Building Society

Skipton Building Society is committed to protecting your privacy and keeping your personal information secure. This policy does not extend to external websites accessed from this site - including those of other members of the Skipton Building Society Group. Please read the terms and conditions of any other sites separately.

## Security

Strict security procedures are followed whenever your information is obtained and stored. Encryption technology is also used to keep the information submitted via the online contact forms secure. Encryption codes information to make it virtually impossible for someone else to read unless they have a key to decipher it. It is then stored in a secure area that can only be accessed by authorised persons.

Open emails are not secure and third parties may be able to intercept, access or alter any information you send via email. Skipton Building Society is not responsible for and cannot accept liability for any damage resulting from open email messages sent to or received by the Society. If you send us an email please keep the amount of confidential information you include to a minimum.

If you make an enquiry via email, we will take steps to check your identity before giving out any personal information.

Emails, alleging to be from UK banks and building societies, have been sent encouraging people to visit fraudulent websites, to invest money and reveal personal details. Skipton Building Society, or companies within the Skipton Building Society group, will never send emails asking for confidential information or security details and you should not respond to emails asking you to reveal such information. We wish to remind customers to be vigilant and if you are unsure or concerned about any communication that seems to be from Skipton Building Society, please call our helpline on 0845 850 1700* 

We regularly review our security procedures.

## Privacy

The Data Protection Act 1998 (see [www.dataprotection.gov.uk](http://www.dataprotection.gov.uk/) for more information) gives individuals certain rights as it defines the rules for processing personal information. It also states that those who record and process personal information, such as the Society, must be open and honest in how the information is used.

The principle purpose of collecting personal data from you via this web site is to assist in the efficient running of your accounts or to provide information or services specifically requested by you. When you complete our online enquiry forms, we ask for your contact details and other selected information so that we can deal with your request as efficiently and effectively as possible.

The Act also allows you to find out what information the Society holds about you in return for a small fee. This is known as a "Data Subject Access Request." If you wish to know what information the Society holds about you, please write to the

Data Protection Officer  
The Bailey   
Skipton Building Society   
North Yorkshire   
BD23 1DN

If any information is inaccurate or incorrect, please inform us and we will correct it.

We provide training for our employees and emphasise the need to keep data confidential.

Your telephone conversations with the Society may be recorded. This is to help the Society in its continuous attempts to improve customer service and to offer additional security. Calls and electronic communications may also be monitored for reasons of staff training.

## Cookies and similar technologies

For the purpose of this policy 'Cookies' and 'similar technologies' will be referred to collectively as 'Cookies'.

### What are Cookies?

Cookies are harmless text files that websites can store on your computer's hard drive when you visit to allow the website to recognise you when you revisit. 

### What are Similar Technologies?

Similar technologies are those which perform a comparable function to cookies, However they are not technically defined as cookies. For more free information please see: [www.aboutcookies.org](http://www.aboutcookies.org/).

### Persistent cookies

These stay on your machine until expiry or deletion (many of these have automatic deletion dates). We use this type of cookie.

### Session Cookies

These are temporary cookies which remain on your machine whilst you are on our web-site. We use this type of cookie.

### What we use cookies for

We use cookies to enable us to gather general management information about web site traffic patterns and to help monitor and improve our internet service. Sometimes we use third parties to assist in analysis, but as we do not collect personal information, no personal information is sent to those third parties.

### We use cookies to:

  * Gather customer journey information across our sites
  * Evaluate advertising and promotional effectiveness
  * Ensure our on-line services work properly for you

Obtain anonymous data that shows visitor numbers to our site. For example, we would be able to see that 1000 people visited our Savings Page yesterday but we could not personally identify these visitors.

### Changing your cookie settings

To enable or disable cookies, follow the instructions provided by your browser (usually located within the "Help", "Tools" or "Edit" facility). Alternatively, an external resource is available at [www.aboutcookies.org](http://www.aboutcookies.org/) providing specific information about cookies and how to manage them to suit your preferences. However, please be aware that disabling cookies may mean that some of our on-line services will not work. 

### Consent to Cookies

If you do not wish to give your consent to our use of cookies, please do not use our web-site.
